LP

Location

Austin, Tx

Phone

(512)-565-1368

Email

Lp1172@yahoo.com

Website

www.greatsiteaddress.com

Luis Pena

An Experienced DevOps Engineer/Software Developer with over eight years of IT experience specializing in Agile software development, back-end development, Linux, web development, cloud computing, and DevOps. I'm pursuing a challenging role at a forward-thinking tech firm where my expertise and experience can be put to good use.

Experience

2019 - Present

DevOps Engineer | Pecan Street Inc | Austin, Tx

- Stood up and maintained barebones, virtual, and cloud servers
- Participated in Project meetings, with technical staff members, business analysts, and external contractors
- Coded ETLs, dashboards, and webpages
- Developed code following common security practices
- Developed shell scripts to track and automate project metrics, ETLs
- Provided database support and maintenance

2018 - 2019

IT Field Service Manager | Integritek | Austin, Tx

- Directed the activities of up to eight field technicians
- Acted as project lead for implementing work standards and procedures
- Oversaw hardware and software issues
- Implemented Active Directory for user accounts and configured end user accounts in Microsoft Exchange

2016 - 2018

Field Service Tech Support | Integritek | Austin, Tx

- Installed and configured computer systems
- Diagnosed and solved hardware and software faults
- Provided hardware and software support

Education

Texas State University | San Marcos, Tx

December 2015 | Bachelor of Science In Computer Science

Key skills and characteristics

- CI/CD pipeline development and implementation
- Scripting for system automation
- Cloud computing platforms (AWS, Linode)
- Version Control Systems (Git)
- Scripting and Programming languages (Python, Java, PHP, HTML, JavaScript, C++, Bash)
- SQL languages (MySQL, PostgreSQL)
- Environment setup and maintenance
- Containerization (Docker)